[
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are the basic elements of an organisation, as discussed by the instructor?",
    "answers": ["Structure, systems, culture, people practices"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following best captures a key element of business strategy?",
    "answers": ["What customer segments you are targeting"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are the reasons that make key capabilies so important? Choose all that apply.",
    "answers": [
      "They help focus the organisation on what it needs to be really good at to succeed with its strategy.",
      "They can form the basis of sustainable competitive advantage.",
      "They help focus leaders by enabling them to prioritize what issues are most important."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The instructor suggests using Porter's frameworks, when identifying key capabilities, for which of the following purposes?",
    "answers": [
      "To go through the key value-adding activities in your organization in a systematic way."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a myth around the use of the Porter's value chain framework?",
    "answers": ["It’s only appropriate for analyzing manufacturing firms."]
  },
  {
    "question": "The operations process in the Porter's value chain framework is defined as_____________.",
    "answers": [
      "The activity of transforming raw materials into finished goods."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is classified as a primary activity in a value chain?",
    "answers": ["Marketing and sales"]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the instructor, which of the following value chain activity is considered important for a consulting firm?",
    "answers": ["HRM"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is classified as a secondary activity in a value chain?",
    "answers": ["HRM"]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the instructor, how can we ensure that our organisation can deliver on its strategy, while at the same time remaining sufficiently agile?",
    "answers": [
      "Break the organization down into its main elements and align those elements with key capabilities"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the instructor, which of the following less useful actions managers tend to fall back on when they try to improve their organisation?",
    "answers": [
      "They either try to re-shuffle job positions or change incentive structures."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following concepts is the answer to the riddle: “Those who live it, ….. understand it, ……. but can’t see it, ….. and those who don’t live it, ……. can see it, ……. but can’t understand it?",
    "answers": ["Culture"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following best describes the adhocracy culture?",
    "answers": ["Innovation, creativity and risk taking"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are the myths that the instructor identifies in the video: Levers of cultural change? (Select all that apply)",
    "answers": [
      "Whatever RE-flects the culture of an organisation can also be used to AF-fect it.",
      "Culture change can therefore be delegated or outsourced to specialists."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the instructor, why is culture difficult to identify in an organisation?",
    "answers": [
      "Culture involves taken for granted values, norms and behaviour"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the instructor, which of the following is the most important reason why cultural change is so difficult?",
    "answers": ["Cultural values tend to define who people are."]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following best describes market culture?",
    "answers": [
      "Externally focused on competitive achievement and will pursue this through very effective systems and processes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Download Scenarios – Week 3 Graded Quiz to complete this quiz. Note: Refer to Scenario 1 to answer quiz questions 1-3. Which structure should you seriously consider as an alternative to the current divisional structure by gym location?",
    "answers": [
      "A matrix structure that leaves the current divisions intact and overlays it with centralised functions for procurement, training methods, finance, HR, and marketing."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Scenario 1 . What is the key trade-off that is in play in the above example?",
    "answers": [
      "The trade-off between the local responsiveness that a decentralised divisional structure gives you on the one hand, and the increased efficiency and coordination that a more centralised structure could give you on the other"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Scenario 1 . What would be a good, valid reason to stick to the existing structure?",
    "answers": [
      "Upon further research you find that customer needs are actually highly localised, because customers really appreciate the feeling that they are dealing with a local business that is run by a person they know, instead of some large, branded corporate"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Scenario 2 for quiz questions 4-6. Which of the following organisation structures is most unlikely to be suitable for your organisation?",
    "answers": [
      "A global functional structure by teaching area, with local principals there for regulatory purposes, local coordination and adaptation, and directing local support functions, but with no direct hiring or supervisory responsibilities over the teaching staff who report into their global function"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Scenario 2 . What is the key trade-off that is in play in the above example?",
    "answers": [
      "The trade-off between local responsiveness and global coordination"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Scenario 2 . What are the conditions under which you could reasonably consider a matrix structure for this organisation?",
    "answers": [
      "Both local responsiveness and global efficiency are really important for your strategy; and your teaching staff is capable of balancing the demands of reporting into two bosses"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Scenario 3 for quiz questions 7-8. With global expansion and additional product lines in mind, what is NOT a convincing reason for considering a functional structure in which sales and marketing is country and product specific, but everything else is centralised globally?",
    "answers": ["This is the most responsive solution"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Scenario 3 for quiz questions 7-8. Under what conditions would you reasonably consider a divisional structure by country with each country director responsible for their own Profit and Loss (P&L)?",
    "answers": [
      "If each country requires a significant amount of adaptation to specific local needs, not just in your sales and marketing approach, but also in software development"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Scenario 4 for quiz questions 9-10. Under what conditions would you reasonably consider a divisional structure by product line, with each product-based Business Unit responsible for its own profit and loss (P&L)?",
    "answers": [
      "The different product lines are so distinct that they require their own specific development teams, manufacturing processes, and sales channels"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Scenario 4 . Why is a divisional structure by country unlikely to be appropriate for this organisation?",
    "answers": [
      "Because local product needs across different countries don’t require any product adaptation, and efficiency is important to the business strategy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Download Scenarios - Week 4 Graded Quiz to complete this quiz Refer to Scenario 1 to answer quiz questions 1-5. Which of the following types of control systems would be most relevant for controlling the plane maintenance issues?",
    "answers": ["Belief systems, Boundary systems, and Diagnostic systems"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Scenario 1 How could you use boundary systems to help address the plane maintenance issues?",
    "answers": [
      "Specify strict maintenance procedures that are also explicit about what is not acceptable practice, and create a safety and compliance function at a senior level in the organisation that carries out regular safety and compliance checks."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Scenario 1 What could help explain the tendency for instructors to rush students through to their exams, even when the student does not feel ready?",
    "answers": [
      "Instructors are rewarded based on the number of students they get through the curriculum, divided by their total teaching hours in a term, regardless of whether the students pass their exam."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Scenario 1 If the training school owned all of the training planes, what would be the best formula for monitoring and managing the cost effectiveness of your planes, assuming that maintenance costs and fuel costs cover all of your plane operating costs, and maintenance costs per plane are fixed?",
    "answers": [
      "Total fuel costs per plane + Total maintenance costs per plane = Total operating costs per plane"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Scenario 1 What would be an example of a useful interactive system for this company?",
    "answers": ["All of the above"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Scenario 2 for quiz questions 6 - 10. How could you use control systems to help prevent client injury due to negligence, which could seriously damage your reputation?",
    "answers": ["All of the above"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Scenario 2 for quiz question 7. If you wanted to increase control over operations, what type of control system would be most important to upgrade in order to obtain the information you need to get a more detailed view of what is going on in each of your gyms?",
    "answers": ["Diagnostic system"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Scenario 2 for quiz question 8. From a financial perspective, what would be the problem with just using net profit for each gym as a basis for comparing their performance?",
    "answers": ["All of the above"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Scenario 2 for quiz question 9. What would be a good example of a useful interactive system measure for this company?",
    "answers": [
      "Systematically keeping track of the latest trends, methods, and equipment in the industry to try and predict what clients will need or expect in the near future"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Scenario 2 for quiz question 10. If the financial incentives of your gym directors were directly tied to net profit of their gym, what would be some of the ways they could artificially bump up their number at the end of the financial year, especially if they think they are not going to be around the following year anyway?",
    "answers": ["All of the above"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Download Scenarios - Week 5 Graded Quiz to complete this quiz. Refer to Scenario 1 to answer quiz questions 1 - 6 By applying the information in the case to Lepak and Snell’s strategic workforce segmentation framework, the new Director of Training should be categorized as a:",
    "answers": [
      "“Critical”, because this role is strategically central, and likely to be relatively difficult to source in the labour market"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Scenario 1 to answer question 2. By applying the information in the case to Lepak and Snell’s strategic workforce segmentation framework, the role of personal trainers that will be reporting into the new Director of Training should be categorized as:",
    "answers": [
      "“Professional”, because the role is strategically central, but should be relatively easy to source in the labour market"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Scenario 1 to answer question 3. The new organisation structure does not leave any room for your former gym directors. Instead, you are going to employ receptionists who are there to open and close the gym, deal with new gym enrolments, client enquiries, and personal trainer bookings insofar as these are not arranged online. These receptionists need to be professional, service-minded, and organised. And finally, you have decided to hire a specialist in gym equipment, who will be in charge of procurement and maintenance of all gym equipment, making sure that your company is always in step with the latest trends, and that all equipment is safe and always in top working order. By applying the information in the case to Lepak and Snell’s strategic workforce segmentation framework, the receptionist role should be categorized as a:",
    "answers": [
      "“Doer” or “Professional”, depending on how strategically central you assess their role to be, which is difficult to determine given the case information"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Scenario 1 to answer question 4. By applying the information in the case to Lepak and Snell’s strategic workforce segmentation framework, the role of Head of Gym Equipment should be categorized as a:",
    "answers": [
      "“Specialist”, because the role is strategically not that central, but likely to be relatively difficult to source in the labour market"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Scenario 1 to answer question 5. A best practice approach to HRM based on theory Y that emphasizes job security and empowerment is not necessarily best in this case because….",
    "answers": [
      "We can’t be sure whether this approach will be effective in Singapore, given that it is based on a theory that is North America-centric"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Scenario 1 to answer question 6. Which of the following is correct? Given the strategic centrality and uniqueness of your new Director of Training …..",
    "answers": [
      "You should adjust your HR practices to the strategically critical nature of this role to ensure that you encourage commitment"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Scenario 2 to answer questions 7 - 10. By applying the information in the case to Lepak and Snell’s strategic workforce segmentation framework, the Global Teaching Area Heads should be categorized as a:",
    "answers": [
      "“Critical”, because this role is strategically central, and likely to be relatively difficult to source in the labour market"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Scenario 2 to answer question 8. By applying the information in the case to Lepak and Snell’s strategic workforce segmentation framework, the role of teaching assistant should be categorized as:",
    "answers": [
      "“Doer”, because the role is strategically not that central, and should be relatively easy to source in the labour market"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Scenario 2 to answer question 9. Which of the following is false? When applying the information in the case to Lepak and Snell’s strategic workforce segmentation framework …..",
    "answers": [
      "School Principals are more unique than Global teaching area heads"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Scenario 2 to answer question 10. Which of the following statements is true for the level of pay you should be considering across the different roles in your organisation?",
    "answers": [
      "None of the above; pay level should not be determined based on the role classifications in the Lepak and Snell workforce segmentation framework"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What course of action does the instructor prescribe in order to define the critical issues facing an organisation?",
    "answers": [
      "Use a 4 step model to diagnose the problems underlying the issue faced by your organisation."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following do you need to be mindful of, when using the 4 step model to define critical issues facing your organisation?",
    "answers": [
      "Don't forget about the importance of existing key capabilities."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the instructor, which of the following is the most important reason there is no such thing as a perfect solution?",
    "answers": ["Solutions always involve trade offs."]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a risk associated with strategy execution?",
    "answers": ["Implementation risk", "Trade off risk", "Flexibility risk"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following DOES NOT relate to the trade off risks?",
    "answers": [
      "The implementation process might be more complex and expensive than anticipated."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following affects work behavior? Choose all options that apply",
    "answers": [
      "Stress experienced at work",
      "Expectations of others at work",
      "Perceptions about the role being performed",
      "Emotions associated with work"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Holland's model, Which of the following types of people are characterized by their problem solving skills? Choose all options that apply",
    "answers": ["Investigative"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Values should ideally fit with which of the following to increase the likelihood of job satisfaction? Choose all options that apply",
    "answers": ["Job characteristics", "Organisational culture"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following strategies used by a manager is likely to overcome a self-fulfilling prophecy?",
    "answers": [
      "Be aware of assumptions made in judging people and situations",
      "Display confidence in employee's competence",
      "Challenge first impressions",
      "Using different sources of information to make decisions"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following best captures the main purpose of the MARS model? Check all that apply",
    "answers": [
      "To understand the sources and factors behind individual behaviour.",
      "To identify how the expectations of others affect work related behaviour"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why do we engage in a homogenisation process? Choose all options that apply",
    "answers": [
      "To process a large quantity of information",
      "To categorise ourselves and others",
      "To define ourselves comparatively"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following combination of values best reflects the ideal values in an organisation?",
    "answers": ["Espoused and aspirational values"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following types of values are explicitly advocated by leaders?",
    "answers": ["Espoused values"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Female workers would less likely do their jobs effectively when they perceive that their work would not get due recognition from their gender discriminating male superiors. Which of the following relationships best generalise this scenario based on the MARS model?",
    "answers": [
      "Behaviour is determined by motivation, which is further shaped by perceptions."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "We simplify our relationships and decision making processes by using which of the following? Check all options that apply",
    "answers": ["Mental Modelling", "Social categorisation", "Stereotyping"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following describe a component of categorical diversity? Check all options that apply",
    "answers": [
      "Professional expertise and world view",
      "Being a member of a profession"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The instructor mentions a study at Apple that found that when teams had members who represented a target end-user, the entire team was more likely to understand that end-user. This study relates to which of the following benefits of diversity?",
    "answers": ["Client diversity"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these options describes positive aspects of the ‘contact hypothesis’ as outlined by the instructor? Choose all options that apply",
    "answers": [
      "The ‘contact hypothesis’ theorizes that interaction changes the way people think, moving them from seeing people in terms of categories to seeing them as individuals.",
      "The contact hypothesis theorizes that working together on a shared project will reduce the prejudice and bias between two groups"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Bringing together people with diverse backgrounds results in knowledge sharing. What is this statement an example of? Choose only one option",
    "answers": ["Value in diversity"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following best reflects our tendency to ignore information that is contrary to our beliefs and values?",
    "answers": ["Confirmation bias"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Having enough money for food and rent is an example of what need in Maslow’s hierarchy? Choose only one option",
    "answers": ["Physiological"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Goals need to be intrinsically motivating for employees. Following the instructor's arguments, which of the following is an implication of this statement?",
    "answers": ["Involve people in setting their own goals"]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the instructor, which of the following answers describes the most important aspects of designing an intrinsically motivating job?",
    "answers": [
      "Goals, feedback on achievement of goals, self-efficacy, reward"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A manager provides employees discretion to respond to customer requests, greater responsibility over planning, scheduling and coordination, and work that does not just follow a narrow set of similar activities. Which of the following elements of the job characteristic theory has the manager activated?",
    "answers": ["Autonomy"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the key components of expectancy theory? Choose all options that apply",
    "answers": ["Instrumentality", "Expectancy", "Valance"]
  },
  {
    "question": "The likelihood that our effort will achieve desired results is captured by which of the following concepts?",
    "answers": ["Expectancy"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following could be considered a limitation of the Two Factor Theory?",
    "answers": [
      "Something can be a dissatisfier or a motivator, based on our perception"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The concept of contingent motivation, discussed in the TED talk 'The puzzle of motivation', best relates to which of the following concepts?",
    "answers": ["Valence"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Theories of motivation show that external (financial) rewards are less useful as a motivating factor. But the instructor has highlighted financial rewards to be important in which of the following situation?",
    "answers": ["When self-efficacy is low and task complexity is high"]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the TED talk 'The puzzle of motivation' , extrinsic (financial) rewards are not suitable for which of the following types of work?",
    "answers": ["Projects involving creative problem solving"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Disagreements are seen in a negative light due to what following reason? Choose only one option",
    "answers": ["They may result in difficult relationships"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the underlying source of conflict? Choose the most correct option. Choose only one option",
    "answers": ["Perceptions"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the most common approach to conflict?",
    "answers": ["Avoiding"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the best approach to conflict?",
    "answers": ["Collaboration"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an approach to conflict that involves giving up something in return for gaining some benefits?",
    "answers": ["Compromising"]
  },
  {
    "question": "How can leaders minimise social loafing?",
    "answers": ["By making work meaningful for their team members"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following can help improve team coordination? Check all options that apply",
    "answers": [
      "The expertise of team members is known",
      "Teams have common resources",
      "When every team member wears a clean uniform"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following types of interdependence means that workers need to work on the task simultaneously?",
    "answers": ["Reciprocal interdependence"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is considered to be the the most important factor in team design ?",
    "answers": ["Team member characteristics"]
  },
  {
    "question": "A disadvantage of team reward systems is which of the following:",
    "answers": ["Team reward systems may increase social loafing"]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the article 'The Secret to Building High-performance Teams', Which of the following is considered to be the best way to facilitate psychological safety?",
    "answers": ["Have one on one conversations to create trust"]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the article 'The Secret to Building High-performance Teams', which of the following types of tasks are considered best done by an individual?",
    "answers": ["Tasks that require creativity and specialisted knowledge"]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the TED talk 'How can groups make good decisions', which of the following is true about the process of arriving at the 'robust average'?",
    "answers": ["Ignore those who are confident but have extreme views"]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the TED talk 'How can groups make good decisions', which groups were more likely to reach consensus?",
    "answers": [
      "Those with members who were categorized as high-confident gray"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the TED talk 'How can groups make good decisions', crowd sourced ideas do not work because of which of the following reasons? Choose all options that apply",
    "answers": [
      "Perceptions and views can be easily influenced",
      "It is easier to agree on simple facts rather than on social issues"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Ethnocentricism is closest to which of the following statements hypothetically associated with a developed country MNE moving to a developing country where child labour is the norm?",
    "answers": [
      "Children should not be engaged in paid work in developing countries."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In some cultures you need address older people as Sir or Ma'am. This best reflects which of the following.?",
    "answers": ["Power distance"]
  },
  {
    "question": "In some cultures people tend to be secretive about their large financial gains lest their relatives turn up to ask for a financial favour. This scenario best matches which of the following cultural dimensions?",
    "answers": ["Collectivism"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following GLOBE Study dimensions relates best to the Hofstede's dimension of Masculinity?",
    "answers": ["Assertiveness"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Decisiveness was rated highly among all cultures, but while decisiveness means fast and general decision-making in the U.S., the French and Germans take it to mean being considerate, slow, and precise in decision-making.' This statement best reflects which of the following about the intercultural dimension of leadership styles?",
    "answers": [
      "The influence of leadership attributes varies due to cultural differences across contexts"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would help promote cultural adjustment of an expatriate employee? Choose all options that apply",
    "answers": [
      "High tolerance for ambiguity",
      "Long honeymoon stage",
      "Small cultural distance"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following ideas are covered in the article 'How cultural factors affect leadership'? Select all options that apply",
    "answers": [
      "Understanding of leadership varies from culture to culture",
      "There are universally acknowledged leadership traits",
      "Charismatic leadership traits are controversial"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The article 'Talent management at multinational firms in China' considers which of the following Hofstede's dimensions as a significant hurdle to hiring and managing local Chinese talent?",
    "answers": ["Power distance"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following could be considered the most significant weakness of Hofstede's model of cultural dimensions?",
    "answers": [
      "Hofstede did not consider the variation in culture inside countries"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Sometimes when people move overseas they experience a condition called 'culture shock'. What are some of the symptoms of 'culture shock' outlined by the industry expert in the video about 'Expatriation'?",
    "answers": ["Anxiety", "Depression", "Homesickness"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is leadership \"more than commonsense' ? Check all that apply",
    "answers": [
      "It often leads to a distorted picture of reality, in which leaders are heroes guiding lesser mortals through the travails of organisational strategy and execution",
      "It can result in passivity in followers - an interpretation of a world in which some are born to lead and others born to follow",
      "The common sense view of leadership tends over-emphasise charisma, willpower and a clear and rational thought process"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why can it be difficult to pursue Evidence-Based Leadership? Check all that apply",
    "answers": [
      "Research evidence is not the central focus of study for many business students, MBAs, or executive education programs",
      "Businesses are characterized by the belief that the particulars of their organization are special and unique",
      "It can threaten managers’ personal freedom to run their organizations as they see fit."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "If you were to design a perfect leader, what qualities would they have? Check only one option",
    "answers": ["High cognitive ability and deep integrity"]
  },
  {
    "question": "If you had a colleague exhibiting counter-productive emotionality in the workplace, what could you do in response? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "Use EQ skills to understand and manage my own reactions to the emotionality and help the person better manage it him or herself"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What best defines people with a high Need for Achievement? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "They are goal oriented, take moderate risks, desire concrete feedback and work hard"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Henry Mintzberg was the first person to empirically research the day-to-day activities undertaken by a CEO. What best defines his findings? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "CEOs have to perform a multiplicity of interdependent roles in fast-paced, fragmented, regularly interrupted environments"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What types of leadership does behavioural research ultimately support? Check all that apply",
    "answers": [
      "Democratic, people-centered, consideration and concern for people",
      "It doesn't support any single leadership style, suggesting there is no one best leadership style in all situations",
      "Autocratic, job-centred, initiating structures and concern for production"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Pygmalion Effect is accurate, which leadership attitude becomes problematic? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "Theory X, as treating people like they are lazy and dislike work will result in them becoming lazy, disliking work and performing less effectively"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why do so many extroverts seem to get into leadership positions? Check all that apply",
    "answers": [
      "It's associated with assertiveness, self-confidence and high energy, all of which seem \"obvious\" leadership traits at lay levels.",
      "Because extroversion was the trait that most seemed to correlate with leadership (i.e.many leaders studied possessed it) in the first scientific studies of the subject",
      "It's a trait culturally celebrated in the USA and American theorists have long dominated the leadership field"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Research into performance predictability suggests that testing General Mental Ability and integrity are the best way to predict future performance. How might this be applied to predictions of leadership ability? Check all that apply",
    "answers": [
      "While it might make sense, there is little established research linking GMA and integrity to effective leadership performance",
      "While it seems to have predictive validity, the concept of GMA is arguably too narrow to be applied to the demands of contemporary interdependent work practice and integrity often predicts compliance, which might not be a useful trait for a leader to have."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these best explains Fiedler's Contingency Leadership model? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "It has 2 styles (task or relationship-oriented) determined by 3 variables (leader-member relationship, task structure, and position power)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these are variables to consider in the Path-Goal model? Check all that apply",
    "answers": [
      "Extent employees defer to others.",
      "Extent employees believe they control goal achievement (internal) or it is controlled by others (external).",
      "Extent of employees’ ability to perform tasks and achieve goals."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the goal of contingency theories of leadership? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "To “fit together” the components of all the pre-existing theories, including the capability and motivation of followers, the personality traits, behaviours and experience of leaders, and the task, structure and environment of the situation."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is it important for leaders to enable a broader social-connectedness between employees in the workplace? Check all that apply",
    "answers": [
      "People with broad organisational knowledge that people like collaborating with seem to add the most value",
      "The act of socialising with other people on a regular basis is increasingly being seen as necessary for maintaining and increasing the information highways within the brain. It helps people think better.",
      "Psychological wellbeing is at risk, as is cognitive performance, if people can't socialise at work"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Collaborative overload suggests that the highest value-adding people in the organisation are also the most: Check only one option",
    "answers": ["Disengaged"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Fred Luthans talks about successful and effective leaders/managers. Which of these behaviours would successful managers excel at? Check all that apply",
    "answers": [
      "Developing good working relationships with people in positional power",
      "Building political coalitions",
      "Learning the written and unwritten rules of the organisational culture and where the power actually lies"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How might you gain in legitimate power? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "Increasing my management experience and building political relationships"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is important to note about the M2 or D2 follower level in the Situational Leadership model? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "An improvement in capability is matched by a decrease in motivation."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How might a Theory Z style leader respond the behaviour of an employee at the D2 or M2 level? Check all that apply",
    "answers": [
      "With a degree of confusion. As such a manager assumes the employee values a working environment in which such things as family, cultures and traditions (which have not changed), why is there a drop in motivation and commitment",
      "By questioning the employee's long-term employment. Is this evidence that now the employee has moved beyond the initial enthusiasm stage, they are actually the wrong fit for the company?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What conceptual and practical challenges are there in employing the situational leadership model? Check all that apply",
    "answers": [
      "Reframing leadership from a hard and natural skillset to a soft and performative skillset",
      "Given the rapidly changing nature and increasing complexity of work, how well can any leader actually perform the leadership styles as they might not have the tehcnical knowhow to judge their employee's level or coach them to improve"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the lecture on team leadership, the instructor identifies which of the following as a key aspect of an industrial organisation? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "There were rigid hierarchies of command and control power systems in industrial organisations"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What do organisations constantly identify as being the number one communicative skill lacking in graduates? Check only one option",
    "answers": ["Writing"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What assumption underpins Vertical-Dyad Theory and LMX? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "That relationships between the leader and followers better predicts follower outcomes than leadership traits of behaviours"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the perceived problem with the \"pragmatic follower\"? Check only one option",
    "answers": ["Their behavior can be viewed as “playing political games”."]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is \"cognitive flexibility\"? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "The ability to see a single problem from multiple perspectives"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What problems are there with the concept of authentic leadership? Check all that apply",
    "answers": [
      "There seems to be a gap in the self-description of authentic leaders and how those who worked with them recognise that description",
      "The research paper that “statistically proves its efficacy” has been criticised for deliberately misrepresenting evidence and for being mathematically incoherent.",
      "There is deep confusion between the psychological and philosophical interpretations of authenticity"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which best defines the bureaucratic cultural form? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "A leadership mind-set that values order, stability, status, and efficiency."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these describes a charismatic leader? Check all that apply",
    "answers": [
      "A leader who possesses a dominant, self-centered, self-aggrandizing and narcissistic personality who uses charisma for self-glorification.",
      "A leader who offers a transformative vision or ideal which exceeds the status quo and then convinces followers to accept this course of action not because of its rational likelihood of success, but because of their implicit belief in the extraordinary qualities of the leader.",
      "A leader with an egalitarian, self-transcendent, and empowering personality who uses charisma for the benefit of others."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following effects are associated with transformational leadership? Check all that apply",
    "answers": [
      "Improved follower organizational commitment.",
      "Improved creativity and decision quality",
      "Improved critical thinking and cogntive flexibility",
      "Improved organizational performance, culture, and learning."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following best relates to a solution to the diversity problem identified in the Tedtalk on diversity by Arwa Mahdawi under the topic 'explore cultural intelligence'? Check only one option",
    "answers": ["Discrimination is often at a subconscious level"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which dimension of authentic leadership is reflected in Bridgewater's methodology of critiquing ideas in a formalised and consistent manner? Check all that apply",
    "answers": [
      "Relational transparency: because the leader is being critiqued and asked questions, it helps him develop a better understanding of his or her authentic self",
      "Internalized moral perspective: it ensures the leader's behaviours are consistent with his or her values",
      "Balanced processing: it ensures the leader gets a cognitively diverse and often challenging set of ideas and interpretations before making a decision to act, meaning they are forced to reflect on personal biases"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a solution suggested by Arwa Mahdawi in her Tedx talk? Check only one option",
    "answers": ["Organise corporate trainings and awareness seminars"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is it about authentic leadership that is most challenging to those trying to capture, theorise and predict good leadership? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "The authenticity that informs the leadership practice seems to come from highly personal and uniquely individual experiences, meaning there is no way it can be codified."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The conceptualisation of culture is typically divided into the \"right culture\" for the organisational type, and strong cultures and weak cultures. Which of the following are behaviours most associated with the concept of strong culture? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "Passion for achievement, results oriented and goal-driven, and learning from mistakes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the reading ' Purposeful leaders’ are winning hearts and minds in workplaces, study finds ' , Which of the following is an important aspect of purposeful leadership? Check only one option",
    "answers": ["Balancing financial goals and social responsibilities"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following was highlighted as a derailer for the low level leadership stage of the opportunist? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "views rules as loss of freedom; views luck as central; rejects critical feedback"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following represent capabilities of an alchemist? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "Attentive to own action, and deeply concerned with multi-faceted perspectives on a given situation or problem"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What best defines adaptive leadership? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "Leadership means influencing the community to face its problems."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is work avoidance in the adaptive leadership model? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "When people resist the pain, anxiety, or conflict that accompanies a sustained interaction with a probelmatic situation and the changes it demands"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an assumption of the adaptive leadership model? Check only one option",
    "answers": ["Problems are embedded in complex and interactive systems"]
  },
  {
    "question": "The instructor mentions Nelson Mandela in which of the following contexts? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "Leaders adapt to challenging situations when they are forced to confront pain."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why should we be sceptical about Simon Sinek's golden circle model of motivation? Check all that apply",
    "answers": [
      "Many of stories that support it seem to be biased, cherry-picked observations of leadership activity",
      "Unlike his claims, the why-how-what model does not mimic the circuitry of the human brain",
      "His summary of the Apple story is a simplistic post-rationalisation, privileging marketing as the core reason for its success"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the Dark Triad?",
    "answers": [
      "Three extremes of personality (psychopathy, narcissism and Machiavellianism)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following best relates to the main conclusion drawn by the instructor about the prevalence of psychopathic behaviours? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "Everyone is capable of exhibiting some of the pyschopathic behaviours in some contexts"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Jeffrey Pfeffer, what are the negative behavioural knock-ons of inspirational modes of leadership and the fables and stories that accompany them? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "Change resistence and change fatigue when it becomes clear inspiration isn’t enough"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Jordan B Peterson, what is leadership? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "It is a manifestation of hierarchical order as a biological imperative, in which superior specimens naturally rise to the top"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Rosalinde Torres in her Tedx video 'What it takes to be a great leader' talks about the three things that are crucial for effective leadership. Which of the following is NOT one of those aspects? Check one option only",
    "answers": [
      "Leaders quickly respond to important trends in their industry."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the YouTube vide 'Dark Side of Japan: Karoshi (Death by Overwork)' what are some of the reasons given by Japanese workers for their extremely long work days? Check all that apply",
    "answers": [
      "Holding back access to work that could be done",
      "Stringing out the work day",
      "Worrying about becoming pregnant"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the article,'Organizational Distrust Is Rampant: Why Leaders Should Be Worried'by Christine Comaford, \"trust of CEOs is at an all-time low\". Which of these options is not an example of one of the three pitfalls that CEOs should try to avoid to regain the trust of their employees? Check only one option",
    "answers": ["Lying and cheating their employees"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Based on the article ‘The cult of compulsory happiness ruining our workplaces ’, employee happiness is important for which of the following work situations? Check only one option",
    "answers": ["A receptionist at a hotel"]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the article ‘ The cult of compulsory happiness ruining our workplaces ’, which of the following intervention is suggested by the author to make employees happy? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "Allow workers uninterruptible time to focus on important tasks"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following best describes the phrase 'vision trap'? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "When there is a disconnect between the tasks that employees do and the bigger organizational purpose"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why was it good strategy by NASA to provide its employees with the ‘concrete objective’ of “putting a man on the moon and returning him safely to earth”? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "Concrete objectives are easier for employees to connect with rather than abstract goals"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When day-to-day activities are meaningful for organizational members, what are they able to better deal with at work? Check all options that apply",
    "answers": ["Challenging tasks", "Low wages", "Dirty and stigmatized work"]
  },
  {
    "question": "While working on a project, a manager encourages one of their employees to utilize multiple skills to complete a task. What job characteristic has the manager used to create meaningful work for their employee? Check only one option",
    "answers": ["Skill variety"]
  },
  {
    "question": "When is meaningful feedback most effective? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "When it comes directly from the work itself, such as a satisfied customer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why shouldn’t a manager always override an employee’s better judgement? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "This makes an employee’s work feel meaningless because it removes their sense of autonomy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Billy was given a work task by his manager. In this task Billy was asked to sit at the front desk and wait to see if a visitor might come through the door. Billy didn’t like to do this job and he thought the job was meaningless. From the options below why do you think Billy thought this job was meaningless? Check only one option",
    "answers": ["Meaninglessness brought on by pointless work"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Lan is an experienced pilot in the Air Force. Lan was asked to fly a fighter jet towards a dangerous situation by her leader and she agreed to take on the mission. Often meaninglessness can happen at work when you put people at risk of physical or emotional harm. Why is Lan’s situation not an example of meaninglessness at work? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "Lan has made an informed choice and understands the risks associated with being a pilot in the Air Force"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Imagine you are a manager and you are developing a position description for a new role at your organisation. You want your new employee to be a ‘close fit’ that aligns with your organisation’s principles and work. As you develop your new position description which of the options below is an important consideration? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "Considering the congruence between work and the employee in terms of their attributes and values"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Amer likes to work with other people. Amer's manager encourages him to talk to his colleagues about new ideas and innovations. Amer feels as though his colleagues respect his work contributions and he believes he is a valuable member of the team. What type of ‘job crafting’ has Amer's manager implemented in this example? Check only one option",
    "answers": ["Relational crafting"]
  },
  {
    "question": "As outlined by the instructor which of these options best describes the term 'framing'? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "Framing is the process of defining a purpose or a set of goals in a particular, meaningful way"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The instructor claims that symbols are important due to two main reasons. What are the reasons she outlines? Check all options that apply",
    "answers": [
      "Symbols are important because they have an effect on our affect (our feelings)",
      "Symbols are important because they have an effect on our cognition (our thinking)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The instructor claims that when people have an affective or emotional response to one object or event, they tend to assign the same meaning and response to a surrounding or related theme. So if people are positive about a symbol, they will tend to be positive about the associated theme. Consider this statement. Rebecca is a leader with a proven record of accomplishments and she often uses symbols at work to effectively create meaning. What might best explain Rebecca's success? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "Rebecca has an accomplished leadership reputation and this helps her to use symbols effectively"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Studies from social psychology tell us that metaphors and analogies are meaningful and persuasive because they: Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "Trigger a state of active thinking as the listener puzzles over the meaning and makes sense of it"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these best describes the term 'social identity'? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "How a person defines themselves in terms of a social group and our emotional attachment to that group"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the video 'the neuroscience of meaning making' the instructor discussed research from the aviation and advertising industry. What similar conclusions do both industries draw in regards to decision-making? Check only one option",
    "answers": ["People make emotional decisions"]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the instructor what is the most common feature found in the most viral TED Talks? Check only one option",
    "answers": ["Personal stories"]
  },
  {
    "question": "A lot of of Shakespeare’s work was written based on the iambic pentameter, using five strong beats and five weak beats. Why did he use this technique? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "Because five seconds was considered the average length of a human breath"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Professor Albert Mehrabian what element is most crucial in building rapport? Check only one option",
    "answers": ["Body language"]
  },
  {
    "question": "The instructor refers to a speech by President Obama and claims that there are a number of key elements present in his storytelling. What are they? Check all options that apply.",
    "answers": ["The villain", "The obstacle", "The solution", "The set-up"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are among the benefits of having higher purpose values? Check all that apply",
    "answers": [
      "Consumers also will be proud of supporting such organizations",
      "It will enable employees to show a greater level of commitment",
      "Employees will be proud of working for the organization"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Phil is a brand manager in a medium size organisation in the FMCG sector. In launching a new brand of a soft drink, Phil has been focusing on promoting the features such as the ingredients, flavours, and the amount of caffeine. Which of the following benefits Phil has been focusing on?",
    "answers": ["Functional benefits"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Consumers may use brands for several benefits. Check all that apply.",
    "answers": [
      "Consumers use brands to better express the self",
      "Consumers brand choice can enable them to be a part of a social group they feel they share identities",
      "Brands may give customers a different experiential vibe.",
      "Consumers use brands to fill the gap between their actual personality and ideal personality."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are among the key strategies Lyft (the ride sharing brand) implemented to distinguish itself from competitors? Check all that apply.",
    "answers": [
      "Positioning the itself based on mission-based values",
      "Focusing on building a more environmentally and socially responsible business",
      "Building consumer goodwill through being a brand activist"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Hamdi Ulukaya, the founder of Chobani yogurt brand, has implemented different strategies focusing on purposeful branding. Which of the following are among the strategies implemented at Chobani? Check all that apply.",
    "answers": [
      "Pursue purpose-focused collaborations",
      "Encourage employee ownership",
      "Shape culture around purpose"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Values like affordability, customer service, quality and innovation belong to which level of brand vision?",
    "answers": ["Such values are core values"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Schweppes, the soft drink brand, which ran the campaign \"Dress to Respect\", is an example of a brand that focuses on which of the following options? Check all that apply.",
    "answers": ["Higher purpose values", "Motivational vision"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Jennifer Aaker conceptualised brand personality proposed 5 categories of personalities. Which of the following represents those 5 categories?",
    "answers": [
      "Sincerity, Excitement, Competence, Sophistication and Ruggedness"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the example of Walmart, which of the following helped Walmart to repair its damaged reputation and regain consumers trust?",
    "answers": [
      "Using its supply chain distribution channels, providing aids to victims of Hurricane Katrina"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Nespresso coffee is a premium coffee brand (www.nespresso.com). A consumer buys Nespresso coffee from Nespresso boutique stores because the consumer feels that she belongs to a club that offers accessible luxury coffee experience. This is an example of which of the following types of brand meaning benefits? Check all that apply.",
    "answers": ["Self-expressive benefits", "Social benefits"]
  },
  {
    "question": "A start-up business owner is considering different options for choosing the brand name, and eventually comes up with the idea of using an animal name, calling the business \"Cheetah\". Which of the following applies to this statement? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "The business owner has adopted the 'Metaphor\" option for the brand name"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Imagine you are a brand manager for a fast-food business with an unhealthy image. You've decided to launch a new brand positioning it as an organic and healthy option. You name the new brand \"Healganic\". Which brand name strategy has the manager applied? Check only one option",
    "answers": ["Fabricated"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Research shows that incomplete letter and word marks can be resulted in a different perception and meaning compared to a complete mark. Check all options that apply",
    "answers": [
      "Incomplete marks can be resulted in perceptions of energetic meaning",
      "Incomplete marks can be resulted in perceptions of less trustworthy meaning",
      "Incomplete marks can be resulted in perceptions of more innovativeness meaning"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Lan is an experienced brand manager, recently tasked to boost the organisation's brand meaning. Conducting market analysis, Lan has decided to form the organisation meaning around agility, activity, and being fast. Lan has several options in communicating such a meaning using brand elements, which of the following are among the most effective tactics that could be implemented: Check all options that apply",
    "answers": [
      "Lan used a tagline: \"born to run\"",
      "Lan adopted a pictorial logo design, using a horse as the logo",
      "Lan used an italic font"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Research finds that circular logos may convey different meanings compared to angular logos Check all options that apply",
    "answers": [
      "Angular logo can signal durability",
      "Circular logo can convey softness",
      "Circular logo can convey comfortableness"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A brand's tagline/slogan is \"lowest prices, every day\". This is an example of Check only one option",
    "answers": ["Descriptive Tagline"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following best describes the logo design of brands like Unilever, Westinghouse, and Tesla Check only one option",
    "answers": ["Letter Marks"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following best describes the logo design of brands like Apple, Lacoste, and Twitter Check only one option",
    "answers": ["Pictorial Design"]
  },
  {
    "question": "A brand has adopted a simple abstract mark for its logo, in which the logo can be interpreted in several ways, the sun, a wheel, or a ball. Such an abstract logo may suffer from... Check only one option",
    "answers": ["Conceptual Complexity"]
  },
  {
    "question": "In order to boost the engagement and conversation, a car manufacturer has used a beauty influencer to endorse its brand. Which of the following is the main challenge of such an endorsement? Check only one option",
    "answers": ["The level of fit between the brand and the endorser"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is organisational alignment?",
    "answers": [
      "Aligning the organisational elements – people, structure, culture, systems – with the key capabilities required for the business strategy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what way are the elements of an organisation comparable to the parts of a human body?",
    "answers": [
      "They need to be attuned to each other for the whole to work effectively"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a reason why key capabilities are important?",
    "answers": [
      "Key capabilities are the things the organisation needs to be really good at to deliver on its business strategy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the best way for identifying key capabilities?",
    "answers": ["Triangulation of all of the above"]
  },
  {
    "question": "The \"substance\" of leadership, as opposed to leading by vision and style, is all about:",
    "answers": [
      "Enabling the organisation to execute the business strategy through the effective configuration of culture, structure, systems, and people practices"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are characteristics of organisational culture?",
    "answers": [
      "It is difficult to change because people become identified with an organisational culture and can resist culture change as a result",
      "It is difficult to identify because most of culture resides underneath the surface level of behaviour",
      "It is difficult to change because it is difficult to identify"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is false?",
    "answers": [
      "A hierarchy culture is generally inferior to the other culture types because it is closely associated with bureaucracy",
      "“Specialists” need to be retained because of their high strategic centrality"
    ]
  },

  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not one of the main reasons why organisational culture is important:",
    "answers": ["Organisational culture eats strategy for breakfast"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why can organisational culture be an important source of competitive advantage?",
    "answers": [
      "Because it is difficult to copy which makes it more sustainable as a potential source of advantage"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements about the matrix structure is true?",
    "answers": [
      "Matrix structures are oriented at coordination along multiple dimensions, such as geography and product line, for example"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When you want to structure a cost conscious organisation that offers a service that centrally involves specialists who are expensive to train, and who can’t be trained across multiple specialisations, which of the following is the most logical structure to use?",
    "answers": ["Functional by specialisation"]
  },
  {
    "question": "The harmonica effect of recurring cycles from centralisation to decentralisation and back again is an effect of which key trade-off?",
    "answers": ["Responsiveness vs Coordination"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is false?",
    "answers": [
      "Organisation structure is the most effective lever for ensuring that the organisation is aligned with the required key capabilities"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the four types of control systems that Professor Robert Simons has defined?",
    "answers": ["Belief, Boundary, Diagnostics, and Interactive systems"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of the four key steps for ensuring that your management reports are linked to your strategy?",
    "answers": [
      "What are the critical measures that enable us to track and influence the Key Performance Indicators (KPIs)?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The main risk of linking KPIs to incentives is that:",
    "answers": ["People may manipulate the KPIs as an unintended consequence"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Beer companies systematically monitoring what the government is thinking and doing in relation to alcohol regulation as an important strategic contingency is an example of:",
    "answers": ["An interactive system"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is true?",
    "answers": [
      "The managerial relevance of IT systems usually comes down to just one thing: \"control\", either performance control or risk control",
      "You should only consider culture change if the behaviours that your existing culture encourages are misaligned with the key capabilities your business strategy requires",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of the key problems that have emerged around HRM?",
    "answers": [
      "HRM has generally failed to secure a seat at the top management table"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A strategic approach to HRM…",
    "answers": ["All of the above"]
  },
  {
    "question": "The main principle of the best practice approach to HRM is …",
    "answers": [
      "To help create an organisational climate that fosters employee competence and commitment through training and empowerment"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is true:",
    "answers": [
      "When you subscribe to Theory Y, your management style is likely to be more participative and focused on empowering your employees to unlock their creative potential and stimulate their commitment to work."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of the four steps involved in moving from a misalignment diagnosis of each of the organisational elements to deciding what organisational changes are required:",
    "answers": [
      "Develop concrete solutions to all of the misalignment issues you have identified using your diagnostic tools"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is generally true?",
    "answers": [
      "Prioritization and focus takes leadership courage because it requires making difficult trade-off decisions that involve risk"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an example of a trade-off risk?",
    "answers": ["All of the above"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following answers is incorrect? Prioritization and focus requires courage from a leader because .....",
    "answers": [
      "Prioritization and focus regularly involve telling people “Perhaps, but not now”, making it seem as if their problems aren’t worth addressing."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Before leaders develop intercultural competence, they need to develop which of the following skills? Please choose the most correct answer. Check only one option",
    "answers": ["Intercultural sensitivity skills"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following Hofstede's dimensions relates to the way a society approaches hierarchies?",
    "answers": ["Power distance"]
  },
  {
    "question": "The GLOBE project focused on which of the following Hofstede's dimensions?",
    "answers": ["Collectivism"]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many leadership styles did the GLOBE project identify?",
    "answers": ["6"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following stages in the model of culture shock adjustment discussed under the topic of expatriation correspond to a situation where expatriates experience overwhelming emotions and become infatuated with the language, people and food in their new surroundings?",
    "answers": ["The honeymoon stage"]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the MARS model, which of the following captures the three most important factors that work together to influence what we do and how well we do it?",
    "answers": ["Motivation, ability, role perceptions"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following best reflect 'openness to experience', which is a key dimension under the OCEAN model of personality?",
    "answers": ["How imaginative, curious, flexible, and sensitive we are"]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to a UK research study quoted by the instructor in the video on 'values and attitudes', which of the following is considered to have the smallest correlation with job satisfaction?",
    "answers": ["Financial rewards"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following represents our basic convictions about preferred ways of doing things or preferred outcomes?",
    "answers": ["Values"]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the instructor,we believe that people are similar within a group and that there are differences between groups. Which of the following concepts best captures this point?",
    "answers": ["Homogenisation"]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the instructor, what is the main criticism of Maslow's Heirarchy model? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "Its claim of upward movement on hierarchy of needs is unrealistic"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "From a leader's perspective, what are some of the most important messages implied in the two-factor theory? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "Recognition for meaningful work is as important as financial reward"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these options best describes the drive to comprehend? Choose only one option",
    "answers": [
      "Our motivation to satisfy our curiosity, to know and understand ourselves, and our environment"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The instructor identifies an example of baseball players who were paid lower than their cohort for three years had a lower batting average which picked up again once their wages returned to the equitable level. This example relates to which of the following theories?",
    "answers": ["Equity theory"]
  },
  {
    "question": "The instructor narrates a story about President Kennedy who visited NASA in 1961 and he introduced himself to a janitor and asked him what he did – the janitor replied “I am helping put a man on the moon!”. Which of the following elements of the Job Characteristics theory does this anecdote relate to? Choose all options that apply",
    "answers": ["Task significance"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What makes teams different from groups?",
    "answers": ["Teams are conscious of shared goals"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following best describes the phrase ‘process losses’? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "Teams taking additional time to complete tasks due to the process"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which stage of the team building process is usually marked by collaborative and trusting interaction among the team?",
    "answers": ["Norming"]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the instructor, a 'gatekeeper' best belongs to which of the following types of roles? Check only one option",
    "answers": ["Relationship related role"]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the instructor, which of the following options is a prerequisite for building self-managed teams?",
    "answers": ["Team members have the required skills to complete the task"]
  },
  {
    "question": "How might we best define the practice of leadership? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "Performing a lot of fragmented and non-routine work at a heavy pace"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The interpersonal roles of leadership are used to: Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "Accomplish objectives, perform rituals and interact with other teams"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which personality trait most correlates with leadership? Check only one option",
    "answers": ["Extraversion"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the four dimensions of Emotional Intelligence?",
    "answers": [
      "Self-awareness, social-awareness, self-managment, relationship management"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these leadership styles shows a high concern for people? Check only one option",
    "answers": ["Country club"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main criticism of contingency leadership theories? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "While they seem good in theory or in the lab, they are complex or unworkable in practice"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A prescriptive leadership model: Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "Tells the user exactly which style to use in a given situation."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is \"power to\"? Check only one option",
    "answers": ["The capacity, ability and willingness to act"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is social-connectedness important to a leader? Check all that apply",
    "answers": [
      "A lack of social-connectedness correlates with poorer psychological wellbeing and cognitive ability",
      "It is the desired outcome of three core political behaviours: Networking, Reciprocity and Coalition Building",
      "Research suggests that highly connected people are also high performing people",
      "It reduces the need for coercive power"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What practices best define informal backstage leadership? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "Thinking and acting differently from the norm, a breadth of social connections and knowledge, collaborative generosity"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does Jeffrey Pfeffer find authentic leadership to be problematic? Check all that apply",
    "answers": [
      "There is good evidence that great leaders continually remake themselves and might thus be inauthentic",
      "The theory is prescriptive and has many call to actions rather than evidence-based"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What three personality profiles constitute the 'Dark Triad'? Check all that apply",
    "answers": ["Psychopath", "Narcissist", "Machiavellian"]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Ron Warren's research approximately how many American workers have reported being bullied at work? And how many American workers actually report that they have been bullied at work? Check only one option",
    "answers": ["37% and 0.05%"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Hostile leadership can lead to what serious health outcomes in organisations? Check all that apply",
    "answers": [
      "Higher rates of heart attacks",
      "Higher rates of strokes",
      "Premature death through stress",
      "Greater staff turnover"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A 1997 study of 511 leaders found that 70 per cent were considered 'loners'. How did the instructor explain why this might be the case? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "They lacked interdependent and socially connected professional relationships"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are negative consequences of meaningless work? Check options that apply",
    "answers": [
      "Poor work performance",
      "High staff turnover",
      "Staff absenteeism"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A study of over 10,000 young people found what characteristic as being the most important in looking for a good job? Check only one option",
    "answers": ["Interesting work"]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the Job Characteristics model what three core job characteristics bring meaningfulness to work? Check options that apply",
    "answers": ["Task identity", "Task significance", "Skill variety"]
  },
  {
    "question": "From the list of answers select three examples related to the term 'job crafting'. Check options that apply",
    "answers": [
      "Changing the quality and amount of interaction with others while working",
      "Changing the content of work",
      "Changing the way we think about our work"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A number of studies suggest that a sense of meaning is increased when there is a ‘close fit’ between an individual’s self-concept and their work role. Why might this be the case? Please select the most correct option. Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "A ‘close fit’ allows employees to express themselves, their values, their beliefs and their perspectives through work"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the motivation of going beyond functional benefits in building meaningful brands?",
    "answers": ["Consumer choice of a brand is based on emotional associations"]
  },
  {
    "question": "In developing a brand vision framework, which of the following are important considerations? Check all options that apply",
    "answers": [
      "Defining core brand vision elements",
      "Keep the brand vision aspirational and motivational",
      "Identify a higher purpose as the overall theme for your brand vision"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Consumers who use brands to improve their personality are? Check only one option",
    "answers": ["Entity theorist"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are the key contributions of building brand personality and meaning? Check all that apply",
    "answers": [
      "Brand personality guides brand-building programs",
      "Brand personality represents and communicates benefits",
      "Brand personality provides energy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to consumer psychology of brand model, the consumers are engaged with brands in three levels Check all that apply",
    "answers": ["Social engagement", "Consumer’s self-centered engagement"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following brand elements is/are not a visual element? Check only one option",
    "answers": ["Tagline/Slogan"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are among the options to choose a brand name? Check all options that apply",
    "answers": ["Metaphor", "Fabricated", "Creative Spelling"]
  },
  {
    "question": "In designing a brand logo, which of the following are among the four typology of logo design? Check all options that apply",
    "answers": ["Word Marks", "Letter Marks", "Abstract Marks"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are among the considerations in crafting brand tagline/slogan? Check all options that apply",
    "answers": ["Competitive", "Provocative", "Imperative and Motivational"]
  },
  {
    "question": "We discussed several meanings that can be communicated via italic fonts, among them were:",
    "answers": ["Fast, Agile", "Active"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the qualities of somebody who possesses \"socialized charisma\"? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "An egalitarian, self-transcendent, and empowering character who uses charisma for the benefit of others."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following options include the four dimensions of authentic leadership? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "Internalised moral perspective, balanced processing, relational transparency, self awareness"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which behaviours are best associated with transformational leadership? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "Idealized influence, inspirational motivation, individual consideration, intellectual stimulation"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the core functional roles of culture? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "To create internal unity and to adapt to the external environment"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What best characterises the femininity dimension of culture? Check only one option",
    "answers": [
      "An emphasis on developing and nurturing personal relationships and a high quality of life"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The term Karl Marx used to refer to a systemic, structural meaninglessness of work within capitalist society was: Check only one option",
    "answers": ["Alienation"]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the video lecture, which of the following statements about alienation is correct? Check only one option:",
    "answers": [
      "Widespread alienation at work is not conducive to a stable society."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements can be inferred from Weber's concept of the spirit of capitalism? Check all options that apply",
    "answers": [
      "The meaning that work has for people in society can predate their lives and concious awareness",
      "If I feel guilty not working when I am supposed to be working, this may be an indication of Weber's spirit of capitalism.",
      "Past religious ideas may have formed our deeply held views regarding business today"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Boltanski and Chiapello's New Spirit of Capitalism the meaning of managerial work in particular has been reinvented since the crises of the 1960s and 1970s. With this in mind, which of the following statements are correct? Check all options that apply",
    "answers": [
      "The meanings applied to managerial work have changed from it being seen as a largely administrative, unglamorous role, to now being written about as an inspiring, charismatic, innovative, authentic activity.",
      "The emergence and dominance of talk of business 'leadership' is an example of Boltanski and Chiapello's New Spirit of Capitalism",
      "The emergence of talk of business today being about such things as ethics, social responsibility, and sustainability is an example of Boltanski and Chiapello's new spirit."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "If Boltanski and Chiapello's arguments about a new spirit of capitalism are correct, then... Check all options that apply",
    "answers": [
      "We might well see another 'new spirit' of capitalism again in coming decades, as developments such as artificial intelligence generate widespread job redundancies and a new crisis of legitimacy",
      "You, as someone interested in a career in management or business, will already be thinking that the work that you do will be exciting, important and inspiring."
    ]
  }
]
